<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teofil Nakov </title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Teofil Nakov </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R function to calculate transitions/transversion ratio of SNPs from a VCF file</title>
      <link>/post/ti-tv-ratio-of-snps-in-vcf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ti-tv-ratio-of-snps-in-vcf/</guid>
      <description>One of the checks if the SNPs called in an analysis are sound, is to take a look at the ratio of transitions to transversions (T_i/T_v). If mutations were random, we expect to see a T_i/T_v of 0.5, because there are twice as many types of transversions as there are transitions. But, of course, transitions (purine-to-purine or pirimidine-to-pirimidine) and transversions (between purines and pirimidines) are not equally likely—transitions are much more common than transitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teofil Nakov</title>
      <link>/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/about/</guid>
      <description>You’ve reached the personal website of Teofil Nakov. I am a biologist working as a postdoctoral researcher in the Alverson lab at the University of Arkansas.
I study various aspects of diatom evolution using laboratory experiments, phylogenetics, and genomics. Diatom taxonomy, especially in ancient lakes, was a focus early on in my studies. In graduate school I tested hypotheses about phylogenetic relationships among species the evolution of adaptive phenotypes. As a postdoc I am learning how diatoms acclimate to changes in salinity at the level of genes and their transcripts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freshwater diatom lineages diversify faster than marine in both planktonic and benthic habitats</title>
      <link>/meeting/xaa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meeting/xaa/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insights into global planktonic diatom diversity: The importance of comparisons between phylogenetically equivalent units that account for time</title>
      <link>/publication/isme-tara/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/isme-tara/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/meeting/xae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meeting/xae/</guid>
      <description>Nakov T, Ashworth MP, and Theriot EC. 2014 Comparative analysis of the interaction between habitat and growth form in diatoms. Joint Aquatic Sciences Meeting (PSA, ASLO, SFS, SWS); Portland, OR, USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/meeting/xaf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meeting/xaf/</guid>
      <description>Nakov T, Ruck EC, Galachyants Y, Likhoshway E, Spaulding SA and Theriot EC. 2013. Phylogenetic Signal, Noise and the Phylogeny of Cymbellales (Bacillariophyceae). Phycological Society of America Meeting; Orlando, FL, USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/meeting/xag/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meeting/xag/</guid>
      <description>Ruck EC, Nakov T, and Theriot EC. Phylogenetic insight into the origins of endemic diatom diversity: The Robustoid Surirellaceae from Lake Ohrid. 2012. Speciation in Ancient Lakes 6, Bogor, Indonesia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/meeting/xah/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meeting/xah/</guid>
      <description>Nakov T, Alverson AJ, and Theriot EC. Using a phylogenetic framework to study the evolution of cell size in the diatom order Thalassiosirales. 2011. International Diatom Symposium, St.Paul, MN, USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/meeting/xai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meeting/xai/</guid>
      <description>Nakov T and Theriot EC. The phylogenetic position of Didymosphenia geminata and evaluating molecular markers for distinguishing populations. 2010. ASLO/NABS meeting, Santa Fe, NM, USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/meeting/xaj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meeting/xaj/</guid>
      <description>Nakov T and Theriot EC. Preliminary molecular phylogeny of the Cymbellales. 2009. Phycological Society of America and North American Diatom Symposium, Iowa Lakeside Lab, IA, USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/meeting/xak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meeting/xak/</guid>
      <description>Nakov T, Spaulding SA and Theriot EC. A preliminary phylogeny of the cymbelloid diatoms using molecular data with emphasis on the genera Didymosphenia M. Schmidt and Navicymbula Krammer. 2008. Phycological Society of America Meeting, New Orleans, LA, USA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>**Nakov T**, Beaulieu JM and Alverson AJ. Diatom diversification through the lense of large sequence, fossil, trait, and diversity databases: Examining the roles of life history strategies and environmental gradients</title>
      <link>/meeting/xab/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meeting/xab/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>**Nakov T**, Ruck EC, and Alverson AJ. Diatom evolution across the plankton-benthos and marine-freshwater divides</title>
      <link>/meeting/xac/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meeting/xac/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>**Nakov T**, Ruck EC, and Alverson AJ. Opportunities and constrains in diatom evolution</title>
      <link>/meeting/xad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/meeting/xad/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publication/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/papers/</guid>
      <description>Google Scholar
Preprints Nakov T, Beaulieu JM and Alverson AJ. Freshwater diatom lineages diversify faster than marine in both planktonic and benthic habitats. Preprint at bioRxiv, p.406165
Onyshchenko A, Ruck EC, Nakov T, Alverson AJ. A single loss of photosynthesis in diatoms. Accepted, American Journal of Botany. Preprint at bioRxiv, p.298810
Papers 2018 Nakov T, Beaulieu JM and Alverson AJ. Insights into global planktonic diatom diversity: The importance of comparisons between phylogenetically equivalent units that account for time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>